P. O. Box AT 1080, Achimota, Ghana +233 243 422 261 richosmanthus@gmail.com

PROFILE

A B.Ed Computer Science degree and an Advanced Certificate in Database Administration holder with a little over three years working experience in the fields of software development, database design and administration, networking, website designing and hosting, and system administration. Quickly learn and master new technology; equally successful in both team and self-directed settings; and proficient in a range of computer systems, languages, tools and testing methodologies. Well organized, dedicated and goal oriented individual with leadership capabilities. In-depth experience of computers in business and associated application such as: Microsoft word, excel, PowerPoint, outlook, SharePoint, MS project etc.

EDUCATION

MA. Economic Policy Management

University of Ghana, Legon, Accra, August 2013 – July 2014 (Ongoing)

Project Work: The transition from analogue to digital broadcasting, an examination of the various options of incentivizing the consumer and its impact on the Ghanaian economy

B.Ed. Computer Science

University of Cape Coast (UCC), Cape Coast, August 2006 - May 2010

Project Work: Promotion and Application Form Online (PAFO).

Description: An Online system that allows senior members and senior staffs of the university to apply for new appointments and promotions through the internet instead of the usual manual system.

Senior Secondary School Certificate Examination (SSSCE)

O'Reilly Secondary School, Accra, September 2000 - April 2003 (Elective Science)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Officer (IT)

National Communications Authority, Accra, March 2012 - till Present

- Coordination of the SIM Registration exercise in Ghana by supervising over 20 contract staff to ensure the smooth verification of mobile phone subscribers to enable the project meet its objectives
- Assisted in the development and maintenance of the Real Time Verification System which is used to verify subscribers in real-time upon SIM Registration
- Supervision of the Authority's IT helpdesk team to effectively deliver prompt IT support to all staff
- Management of the Authority's current website (https://nca.org.gh) by regularly updating and improving certain features and content of the site.
- Currently leading a development team to redesign the Authority's website to enhance its look and feel and also bring up to scale with current web technologies.
- Developed a Type Approval and Dealership License portal (http://verify.nca.org.gh) for the Authority to enable its customers apply for these services online
- Management of the software applications which are database driven by providing first hand support to the applications
 (ASMS system for Spectrum analysis and monitoring, ASCOM QoS system for the monitoring and measurements of
 the quality of service of the various mobile network operators, and the PERSOL & PASTEL systems for the
 Accountants) to enable the Authority deliver on its core mandate

Database Assistant, Contract (IT)

National Communications Authority, Acera, August 2011- March 2012

• Lead a team at the Ghana Passport office to convert all of its old issued passports data from the paper-based unto a spreadsheet application for the purpose of the then SIM Verification exercise

P. O. Box AT 1080, Achimota, Ghana +233 243 422 261 richosmanthus@gmail.com

- A liaison between the mobile network operators and the Authority for the submission and verification of data on registered SIM subscribers
- Collated the statistics of the registered and verified SIM subscribers in Ghana
- Provided IT support to the staff of the Authority
- Assisted in the maintenance and troubleshooting of the Authority's core network infrastructure
- Developed a Clearance database application portal for management of the clearance and inspection of telecommunication equipments at the various ports in Ghana

National Service Personnel

National Communications Authority, Accra, October 2010 - July 2011

- Provided IT helpdesk support to the staff of the Authority
- Joined a committee to carry out a revenue collection exercise for the authority
- Joined the SIM Registration exercise team to carry out monitoring of the registration exercise on the field across the length and breadth of Ghana.
- Assisted in the updating of the Authority's website content.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Certificate: Emerging Managers Development Training University of Ghana Business School, October 2014 Legon, Ghana
- Certificate: Zend Certified PHP Engineer

Zend Technologies Ltd.

Koenig Solutions PVT, India, August 2014

http://www.zend.com/en/yellow-pages #show-Client Candidate ID=ZEND 025987

- Certificate: Scalable Network Infrastructure African Network Operators Group (AfNOG), June 2014 Djibouti
- Certificate: Introduction to ICT Policy and Regulation
 Commonwealth Telecommunications Organisation, July 2013
 Akosombo, Ghana
- Certificate: Competition and Convergence Commonwealth Telecommunications Organisation, July 2013 Akosombo, Ghana
- Certificate: Scalable Internet Services
 African Network Operators Group (AfNOG), June 2013
 Lusaka, Zambia
- Certificate of Appreciation: West African Cybersecurity and Cybercrime workshop
 United States Department of State and the United States Department of Justice, January 2013
 Accra, Ghana
- Certificate: CCNA
 Ghana Institute of Management and Public Administration (GIMPA), July 2013
 Accra, Ghana

P. O. Box AT 1080, Achimota, Ghana +233 243 422 261 richosmanthus@gmail.com

- Certificate: Advanced Certificate in Database Administration
 Ghana Institute of Management and Public Administration (GIMPA), October 2012
 Accra, Ghana
- Certificate: Wireless Network Security Workshop Ghana Telecom University College (GTUC), September 2011 Accra, Ghana

CONFERENCES / WORKSHOPS ATTENDED

• Annual Cybersecurity Forum, April 2013 Yaounde, Cameroon

 ITU-T Study Group 11: Signalling and Test Protocols Specifications International Telecommunications Union Headquarters, March 2013 Geneva, Switzerland

Microsoft OPEN DOOR Conference
 Accra International Conference Centre, April, 2011
 Accra, Ghana

SKILLS

• IDE: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Dreamweaver

• Hosting: Virtual Hosting (using apache on Ubuntu Linux Server), CPanel

• **Data Recovery tools:** TuneUp Utilities, Power Data Recovery

• **Methodologies:** Waterfall, RAD.

• XML: XML Schema, DTD, XPath

Programming Languages: C++, PHP, SQL, XML, HTML, JavaScript, CSS
 Servers: Windows Server 2003 and Ubuntu Linux Server

• Operating Systems: Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7, Server 2003, Linux (Ubuntu Desktop,

Ubuntu Server)

Virtualization Platform: Oracle VirtualBox, VMWare,
 RDBMS/Tools: MySQL, Microsoft Access

• Networking: Subnetting, Routing, Cabling, Trunking

• Content Management: Drupal, Wordpress

• Languages Spoken: English, Fante, Twi, Dagomba, Hausa, Ga

INTERESTS / ACTIVITIES

- Reading: Computing magazines, Technology News Letters, Science books,
- Listening to Music: Classical music, Hymns, Gospels, Reggae, Country music
- Playing scrabble
- Playing Snooker/Pool
- Swimming
- Teaching: ICT, Mathematics, Web Programming

P. O. Box AT 1080, Achimota, Ghana +233 243 422 261 richosmanthus@gmail.com

REFERNCES

• Kenneth Adu-Amanfoh

Deputy Director, IT National Communications Authority Cantonments, Accra Kenneth.adu-amanfoh@nca.org.gh 0246339296 or 0299400415

• George Ollenu

Fmr. Director, Administration National Communications Authority Cantonments, Accra 0243484466

• John K.E. Edumadze

University of Cape Coast Coordinator of IT Center / Lecturer jedumadze@ucc.edu.gh or edumadze@excite.com 042-30859/60 or 0243942749